A Guide to the Pocahontas Mines Collection, 1883-1997
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Pocahontas Mines Collection, 1883-1997
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2004-002
Digital copies of items in Series I, Scanned Rolls are available. An inventory of the scanned rolls is available to view online; descriptions are currently in progress. Please contact Special Collections to request a copy of an image.
ca. 600 Cubic Feet; 798 boxes
The Pocahontas Mines Collection, 1883-1997, documents the mining operations of CONSOL Energy, Inc. and its predecessor coal mining companies in the Pocahontas, Virginia, area, including numerous counties in southwest Virginia and eastern West Virginia. The collection is divided into four series based on type: Scanned rolls, Unscanned rolls, Books, and Ledgers. The scanned and unscanned rolls are primarily of mining maps and related oversized items, such as mechanical building and equipment drawings, plats, and topographic maps. The books and ledgers generally relate to mining surveys.
Consol Energy, Inc
Consolidated Coal Company (Luzerne County, Pa.)
Pocahontas Fuel Company, Inc.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. A few files are restricted for confidentiality, and these are identified in the inventory.
Acquisition Information
The Pocahontas Mines Collection was donated to Special Collections between 2004 and 2009.
Alternate Form Available
Digital copies of items in Series I, Scanned Rolls are available. An inventory of the scanned rolls is available to view online; descriptions are currently in progress. Please contact Special Collections to request a copy of an image.
Historical Note
Named for its proximity to Pocahontas, Virginia, and Great Flat Top Mountain in West Virginia, the Pocahontas Coalfield or Flat Top-Pocahontas Coalfield spans 900 square miles along the Virginia-West Virginia border. Discovered in the mid-1800s, local blacksmith Jordan Nelson started selling coal from his land in the 1860s. During the Civil War, Confederate cartographer Jedidiah Hotchkiss boasted about the coalfield in his publications and in 1876 exhibited at the Philadelphia Centennial Exposition.
In 1881, the town of Pocahontas, Virginia, was founded to support the mining operations, and two years later the first mine in the coalfield was opened to Pocahontas Seam #3. A number of competing mining and land companies developed in the 1880s around the Pocahontas Coalfield. Several Philadelphia businessmen joined forces to establish the Norfolk & Western Railroad (later the Norfolk & Western Railway) to transport coal out of the coalfield, the Flat Top Land Association to manage land holdings, and the Southwest Virginia Improvement Company to develop mining operations.
The Flat Top Land Association (later Flat Top Land Company) leased land in the area to independent miners. John Cooper formed the Mill Creek Coal & Coke Company in 1884, J.P. Bowen founded the Booth-Bowen Coal & Coke Company, and William McQuail operated the Turkey Gap Coal & Coke Company. Jenkin Jones began leasing from Flat Top in 1885. By 1907, he established the Pocahontas Consolidated Collieries Company, Inc. of West Virginia, later Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., by merging numerous mining companies together.
In 1901, J. P. Morgan of U. S. Steel acquired the Flat Top Land Company, reorganizing it into the Pocahontas Coal & Coke Company of New Jersey, and the Southwest Virginia Improvement Company became the Pocahontas Fuel Company of New York. At this time, the Norfolk & Western Railway purchased land from Morgan in a deal granting him acreage to form his United States Coal & Coke Company at Gary, West Virginia. In 1939, Pocahontas Coal & Coke became Pocahontas Land Corporation, chartered in Virginia, and in 1977, the company chartered the Pocahontas Kentucky Corporation, later the Pocahontas Development Corporation. In 1982, Norfolk & Western merged with the Southern Railway as Norfolk Southern.
In 1860, several Maryland coal operators merged their companies into the Consolidation Coal Company. The company began mining operations in West Virginia when it acquired the Fairmont Coal Company in 1903. After further expansion, Consolidation Coal merged with the Pittsburgh Coal Company into the Pittsburgh Consolidation Coal Company in 1945. In 1956, the company acquired the Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., and in 1991, DuPont Energy and RWE A.G. acquired and changed the company's name to CONSOL Energy, Inc.
SOURCES:
McGehee, Stuart, and Eva McGuire. A Century of Stewardship: The History of Pocahontas Land Corporation. Bluefield, WV: Pocahontas Land Corporation, [2001].
CONSOL Energy Inc. "Our History." Accessed November 2014. http://www.consolenergy.com/about/our-history
Norfolk and Western Historical Society. Talk Among Friends, Special Anniversary Edition, March 2013. http://www.nwhs.org/eTAF/NWHS.eTAF.2013_02.web.pdf.
Town of Pocahontas. "Exhibition Mine and Museum." Accessed November 2016. http://pocahontasva.org/museum.html (archived version on Wayback Machine).
Wikipedia. "Pocahontas Fuel Company Store and Office Buildings." Accessed November 2016. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pocahontas_Fuel_Company_Store_and_Office_Buildings.
Wikipedia. "Pocahontas Coalfield." Accessed November 2016. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pocahontas_Coalfield.
Wikipedia. "Pocahontas Exhibition Coal Mine." Accessed November 2016. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pocahontas_Exhibition_Coal_Mine.
Wikipedia. "CONSOL Energy Mine Map Preservation Project." Accessed November 2016. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Consol_Energy_Mine_Map_Preservation_Project
Scope and Content
The Pocahontas Mines Collection, 1883-1997, documents the mining operations of CONSOL Energy, Inc. and its predecessor coal mining companies in the Pocahontas, Virginia, area, including numerous counties in southwest Virginia and eastern West Virginia.
The collection is divided into four series based on type: I. Scanned rolls, II. Unscanned rolls, III. Books, and IV. Ledgers. The scanned and unscanned rolls are primarily of mining maps and related oversized items, such as mechanical building and equipment drawings, plats, and topographic maps. The books and ledgers generally relate to mining surveys.
Series I. Scanned rolls, 1891-1992, contain 3475 maps in 261 boxes, totaling approximately 135 cu. ft. Most of these rolls are mining or mine survey maps, and when possible, the maps are identified with title, company, coalbed, mine name, county, state, USGS quadrangle, dates, and notes. Related scanned rolls are identified by CON number, and some related items are unscanned and identified in Series II. The items in this series have been scanned, and their digital file ids are the CON# (e.g. CON1_1 or CON3209) assigned by the DMME. Some maps also have OSM Doc, MSHA, and/or USBM numbers.
Please note: An inventory of the scanned rolls is available to view online; descriptions are currently in progress. Please contact Special Collections to request a copy of an image.
Series II. Unscanned rolls, 1883-1997, contains 463 boxes, totaling approximately 360 cu. ft. Most rolls are mining and topo maps, mechanical and architectural drawings, and photographs that have not been scanned. Some rolls may be duplicates, very similar to, or of the same mine/area as scanned maps in Series I and are noted when possible by identifying the CON digital file number (e.g. "similar to CON2501" or "see also CON153").
Series III. Books, 1914-1995, contains 2940 vols. in 62 boxes, totaling 64.48 cu. ft. It consists of mainly field notebooks from mine surveys and some related papers for surveys. There are publications in boxes B61 and B62.
Series IV. Ledgers, 1916-1993, contains 42 boxes, totaling 45.02 cu. ft. It primarily consists of survey record books (not field notebooks). Many record "Survey By", "Traverse by", Notebook No., Page No., Station, Azimuth, Reduced Vernier, Cosine, Horizontal Distances, Sine, Latitude (North and South), Departure (East and West), Sums of Latitude (N&S) and of Departure (E&W), Remarks. N.B.: TT looks like pi sometimes.
Arrangement
The Pocahontas Mines Collection is divided into series based on material type:
Series I. Scanned rolls, 1891-1992
Series II. Unscanned rolls, 1883-1997
Series III. Books, 1914-1995
Series IV. Ledgers, 1916-1993
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Materials
The Archives & Special Collections in the University of Pittsburgh Library System has two collections from CONSOL Energy Inc. related to mining operations in Pennsylvania, CONSOL Energy, Inc. Mine Maps and Records, 1857-2010, AIS.1991.16 and Consolidation Coal Company Records, 1854-1971, AIS.2011.03
Index Terms
Subjects:
Coal mines and mining; Tazewell County (Va.); Virginia; West Virginia
Organizations:
Consol Energy, Inc; Consolidated Coal Company (Luzerne County, Pa.); Pocahontas Fuel Company, Inc.
Contents List
- Series I. Scanned rolls, 1891-1992, 135 Cubic Feet; 261 boxes (3475 items)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I. Scanned rolls, 1891-1992, contain 3475 maps in 261 boxes, totalling approximately 135 cu. ft. Most of these rolls are mining or mine survey maps, and when possible, the maps are identified with title, company, coalbed, mine name, county, state, USGS quadrangle, dates, and notes. Related scanned rolls are identified by CON number, and some related items are unscanned and identified in Series II. The items in this series have been scanned, and their digital file ids are the CON# (e.g. CON1_1 or CON3209) assigned by the DMME. Some maps also have OSM Doc, MSHA, and/or USBM numbers.
  Please note: An inventory of the scanned rolls is available to view online; descriptions are currently in progress. Please contact Special Collections to request a copy of an image.
- Series II. Unscanned rolls, 1883-1997, 360 Cubic Feet; 463 boxes
  Series II. Unscanned rolls, 1883-1997, contains 463 boxes, totalling approximately 360 cu. ft. Most rolls are mining and topographical maps, mechanical and architectural drawings, and photographs that have not been scanned. Some rolls may be duplicates, very similar to, or of the same mine/area as scanned maps in Series I and are noted when possible by identifying the CON digital file number (e.g. "similar to CON2501" or "see also CON153").
  - No Mine Workings, Maitland #4 Rock Fall, 1981/02 (Box 007)
  - OSM #700164, Peerless Tipple, Norfolk and Western Railway (Box 035)
    Includes CON165, CON 926-CON932
  - OSM #700742, "Inactive", Turkey Gap, Wenonah No. 1 Mine, 1921-1924 (Box 101)
  - OSM #700260, Mathews Mine No. 1, Consolidation Coal Company - Tennessee Division, undated (Box 107)
  - Four-mile Branch Project contour maps, facilities and plans, Elkhorn No. 1 Seam, Jones Fork, Consolidation Coal Company of Kentucky, Knott County, Kentucky, 1989-1990 (Box 135)
  - OSM #700546, Houston No. 12 Seam (Box 148)
  - Royal Crown Coal Co., West Virginia Property Map, 31. BU-26, Nicholas-Fayette Greenbrier Co., West Virginia (Box 169)
    Includes CON2469
  - OSM #700265, Island Creek Coal Co., Coal Mountain No. 9, Powellton Seam (2 maps), 1949, 1952 (Box 183)
  - Bishop Schedule Production graph; Pocahontas Land Corporation, Gilliam Coal & Coke Company, and Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc. map; and engineering notes (Box 226)
  - Map showing Town of Pocahontas with Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc. chart (Box 230)
  - Outside Traverse, Origin Unknown, Itmann (Box 230)
  - Sagamore Property Map (Box 230)
  - Cherokee Property Map (Box 230)
  - Project Plan Mine Development, J.B. & B. Colliery Company Mines, Wyoming County, West Virginia (Box 231)
  - Strip mine map, unidentified location (Box 231)
  - Big Vein Lots No. 114, Crozer Coal and Land Company, Parcel Nos. 1-6, along North Fork of Elkhorn Creek and West Virginia Highway No. 17 (Box 231)
  - Itmann, West Virginia, town map with houses and buildings, including West Virginia Armature Company and Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc. (Box 231)
  - Map showing lease property boundaries and boreholes (Box 232)
  - Piedmont No. 11 seam (Box 232)
  - Aerial photo with parcels and parcel numbers (Box 232)
  - Property map of Simmons Creek, Jones Hill (Box 232)
  - No mine workings, record of drill hole no. 58, on left fork of Indian Creek, Tazewell County, Virginia, 1937 (Box 233)
  - No mine workings, record of drill hole no. 57, located on Grassy Spring Fork of Indian Creek, Tazewell County, Virginia, 1937 (Box 233)
  - Plan and profiles showing proposed additions to no. 4 shop at Kimball for supply house and car shop, 1945 (Box 233)
  - Norfolk and Western Railway Company, New River division, Guyandotte river branch, proposed siding facilities to serve, Kepler Mine, Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., division of Consolidation Coal Company, West Virginia, 1968 (Box 233)
  - Consolidation Coal Company, Red Fox Project, McDowell County, West Virginia; Leaseholders and Drill Hole Sights in Lower Horsepen, Middle Horsepen, Nos. 8-11 and 9L Seams with contours shown, no mine workings, 1983 (Box 233)
  - No mine workings, Pocahontas Consolidated Collieries, Pocahontas Plant, map detailing school located northeast of church, 1909/04/19 (Box 233)
  - No mine workings, Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., Pocahontas Plant, house layout on old ovens, 1922/10/04 (Box 233)
  - No mine workings, record of planned drill hole 59, located on Bearwallow Fork of Indian Creek, Tazewell County, Virginia, 1937/06/30 (Box 233)
  - Negatives: 3 contour maps of Tennessee and Kentucky and two copies of Property Map, Indian Creek Field, Block Coal and Coke Corporation, 1943/10/26 (Box 233)
  - No mine workings, Relation of Southern Coal Measures with Principal Railroads to Certain Electric Power Systems, 1953/06/01 (Box 233)
  - Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., Big Vein Subdivision Lands, no mine workings, 1953/10/31 (Box 233)
  - 2 maps: No. 3 Seam and No. 4 Seam, Sheet No. 6 and Sheet No. 7, prepared by Aerial Map Services Co., Johnstown and Jacobs Fork, 1963/06 (Box 233)
  - No mine workings, No. 3 Seam, No. 4 Seam, Borehole locations, 1963/06 (Box 233)
  - No mine workings, Bishop Prep Plant, Thickener Location, 1967/06/02 (Box 233)
  - Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., Tolliver Branch Coal Refuse Disposal Facility, Crane Creek Mine, Mercer County, West Virginia, no mine workings, 1975/10/09 (Box 233)
  - Profile of Bishop Building site supply yard and parking area, no mine workings, 1979/03/14 (Box 233)
  - topographic map of Whitesville quadrangle, ca. 1960s (Box 233)
  - Meadow Branch No. 2 Mine, profile of slope, no mine workings, undated (Box 233)
  - Unknown mine, Profile of King Slope, Vertical and Horizontal Slope, no mine workings (Box 233)
  - G and A Coal Company, cross section, no mine workings, No. 2 Mine (Box 233)
  - No mine workings, record of drill hole no. 56, on Grassy Spring Fork of Indian Creek, Tazewell County, Virginia (Box 233)
  - OSM #700419 Coal profile (Box 233)
  - Unknown No. 11 Seam, Pinnacle/Crystal (Box 233)
  - Knox and Clay counties, Kentucky, test bore, topographic map (Box 233)
  - Borehole placements, no mine workings (Box 233)
  - Safety bulletins (Box 233)
  - Unidentified section of a map (Box 233)
  - OSM #700008.07, Map of Itmann Coal Company No 3 mine, 1983/08/01 (Box 234)
  - Drillhole data for Drillhole No. 1 thru No. 3, L.J. Hughes & Sons Inc., 1966/11-1966/12 (Box 234)
    Detailed strata layer data from diamond drilling.
  - Five untransferred (reversed image) maps on brown transfer paper (Box 234)
  - Eastern Gas and Fuel Associates, Coal division, Traverse Sheets of Carswell Mine. (Box 234)
    Surveyors Traverse data including Azimuths and Closure Calculations.
  - used map transfer paper sheets (Box 234)
  - Topographic Map of Virginian Lear Coal Field No. 2, State of Kentucky, 18 sheets. (Box 234)
  - Fire Creek Test Holes (Box 234)
  - Part of OSM #700236, Summers Drift Topographical Profiles No. 1 & 2 (Box 234)
  - Map Showing Two Acre Tract, Lying in Mercer Co., West Virginia. at Club's Junk Yard - part of Pocahontas Townsite. (Box 234)
  - Map Showing Lands to Be Added to Itmann Leasehold (Box 234)
  - Map Showing Beach Property, Pocahontas, Virginia. (Box 234)
  - Map Showing, Morris Harrison, 1.69 ac. Tract on Waters of Indian Creek, Tazewell Co., Virginia. (Box 234)
  - Map Showing Lands of Mrs. Mary Chuchuck. Lying near Wolfe, Mercer Co., West Virginia. (Box 234)
  - Map showing Lots 7,8,9,10 of the J.P. Havens Estate (Box 234)
  - Map Showing Area Required for Slate Dump (Box 234)
  - Map Showing the W.M. Hearn 34 Ac. Tracts lying on Flat Top Mountain near Hearn's Gap, Mercer Co., West Virginia (Box 234)
  - Map showing the D.A. Lockhart 17.5 Ac. Mineral Tract Lying on the Waters of the Panther Branch in Tazewell Co., Virginia. (Box 234)
  - Untitled Map showing land parcels on Slate Creek near Grundy, Virginia. (Box 234)
  - Untitled Map showing Land Parcels on and around the Rockhouse Fork. (Box 234)
  - Profile of Bottom of Slope No. 2 in No. 2 North Main. (Box 234)
  - OSM #700662.08, Matthews Mine No. 1, Tennessee Division, Consolidation Coal Co., Areas Mined in 1987. (Box 235)
  - OSM #700662.11, Matthews Mine No. 1,Tennessee Division, Consolidation Coal Co., Areas mined in 1984. (Box 235)
  - Boissevain Belt Line (Box 235)
  - Adverse Surface, Map #24025, VICC Land Company of ANR Coal Company. (Box 235)
  - Adverse Surface, Map #24923, VICC Land Company of ANR Coal Company. (Box 235)
  - Topography Along Pinnacle Creek (Box 235)
  - Sections Showing Proposed Change in Channel (Box 235)
  - Untitled Contour Mining Blueprint (Box 235)
  - Pocahontas Consolidated Colleries Co. Guyandotte Property (Box 235)
  - A Prospecting Map of a Part of the P.C. & C. Co's. Unleased Lands. (Box 235)
  - Map of Land Showing Lands of Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc. a Division of Consolidation Coal Company, and adjacent territory. (Box 235)
  - Map of Land Showing Lands of Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc. a Division of Consolidation Coal Company, and adjacent territory. (Box 235)
  - Map of Land Showing Lands of Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc. a Division of Consolidation Coal Company, and adjacent territory. (Box 235)
  - Map of Norfolk & Western Railroad Cost figure zones (Box 235)
  - Rowland land Company, Powellton Coal Seam Prospecting Map on Clear and Marsh Fork (Box 235)
  - Rowland land Company, Big Eagle Coal Seam Prospecting Map on Clear and Marsh Fork (Box 235)
  - Boreholes No. 61 and 61 on Keowee and Valls Creek, New River and Pocahontas Consolidated Coal Co., 1937 (Box 236)
  - USGS topographic Map of Keystone Quadrangle, West Virginia, 1979 (Box 236)
  - Proposed Extension to Build Ground - General Plan, Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., 1919/12/23 (Box 236)
  - Map of Pulaski Iron Co., Eckman, West Virginia, 1922/01/26 (Box 236)
  - Jenkin Jones #7 Washery heating plant, Boiler house details, 1926/07/15 (Box 236)
  - White Church: Building Plans. Amonate, Virginia. Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., 1934/12/31 (Box 236)
    Church was built using by Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc.
  - Map of Bois Fill Station plans, Boissevain, Virginia, 1941/4/11 (Box 236)
  - Map of Future Projections in No. 2 Gas Seam of Rowland Mine, Consolidation Coal Company, 1973/05/10 (Box 236)
  - Pollution Abatement Proposal (version drawn in ink), Matthews Mine No. 1 & Plant Area, 1975/04 (Box 236)
    Shows proposed Changes to plant operations to include a coal slurry impoundment and Mine waste water capture ponds.
  - Pollution Abatement Proposal (version drawn in pencil) Matthews Mine No. 1 & Plant Area, 1975/04 (Box 236)
  - 1988 Drilling and Exploration Activity, Consolidation Coal Company, East Kentucky Operations map and memo, 1987/10/21 (Box 236)
  - Pageton Disturbed Area profiles No. 1 - No. 6 (4 sheets), undated (Box 236)
  - Pageton Preparation Plant Settling Pond Profiles (10 sheets), undated (Box 236)
  - Map of unidentified Surface Coal Mine, undated (Box 236)
  - Cut and Fill Plans A and B, Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., undated (Box 236)
  - Topographical Map of Amonate Impoundment Pocahontas Coal Co, undated (Box 236)
  - Map of Tennessee Mining and Manufacturing Company Property in Anderson, Campbell, and Scott counties, TN (Box 236)
    Multiple sheet photocopies of very large map.
  - Coalburg Seam Thickness Map, Rowland Reserve, Consolidation Coal Company (Box 236)
  - Lower Coalburg Seam Thickness Map, Rowland Reserve, Consolidation Coal Company (Box 236)
  - Winifrede Seam Thickness Map, Rowland Reserve, Consolidation Coal Company (Box 236)
  - Taylor Seam Thickness Map, Rowland Reserve, Consolidation Coal Company (Box 236)
  - Chilton Seam Thickness Map, Rowland Reserve, Consolidation Coal Company (Box 236)
  - Hernshaw Seam Thickness Map, Rowland Reserve, Consolidation Coal Company (Box 236)
  - Upper Peerless Seam Thickness Map, Rowland Reserve, Consolidation Coal Company (Box 236)
  - Lower Peerless Seam Thickness Map, Rowland Reserve, Consolidation Coal Company (Box 236)
  - Upper Gas Seam Thickness Map, Rowland Reserve, Consolidation Coal Company (Box 236)
  - Lower Gas Seam Thickness Map, Rowland Reserve, Consolidation Coal Company (Box 236)
  - Powellton Seam Thickness Map, Rowland Reserve, Consolidation Coal Company (Box 236)
  - Upper Eagle Seam Thickness Map, Rowland Reserve, Consolidation Coal Company (Box 236)
  - Middle Eagle Seam Thickness Map, Rowland Reserve, Consolidation Coal Company (Box 236)
  - Lower Eagle Seam Thickness Map, Rowland Reserve, Consolidation Coal Company (Box 236)
  - Depth to Top of Lower Eagle Coal Seam Map. Rowland Reserve, Consolidation Coal Company (Box 236)
  - Record of Drillhole No. 60 on Left Fork of Grassy Spring Fork of Indian Creek, Tazewell County Virginia. New River and Pocahontas Consolidated Coal Co. (Box 236)
  - Elevations and Section views for Drift Mouth Entrance to Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc. (Box 236)
  - Large photo negative of topographic map of unidentified area. (Box 236)
  - Topographical Map showing mine locations around Pageton, West Virginia. d (Box 236)
  - Topographical Map of unidentified area (Box 236)
  - OSM #700662, Matthews Mine No. 1, Consolidation Coal Co. Areas mined in 1984. (Box 236)
  - No. 14 mine, Beckley Seam, 1947 (Box 237)
  - Aerial Photographs: 129-2C-6 thru 9, 1952 (Box 237)
  - Aerial Photographs: 658: 429-434, 1955 (Box 237)
  - Aerial Photographs: 658: 271-280, 1955 (Box 237)
  - Aerial Photographs: 658: 515-521, 1955 (Box 237)
  - Aerial Photographs: 658: 187-190, 1955 (Box 237)
  - Aerial Photographs: 658: 354-364, 1955 (Box 237)
  - Aerial Photographs: Horsepen Bishop, 1955 (Box 237)
  - Aerial Photographs: DZL-5R-160, 1957 (Box 237)
  - Aerial Photographs: DZL-1R-232, 1957 (Box 237)
  - Aerial Photographs: DZL-5R-29 thru 33, 1957 (Box 237)
  - Aerial Photographs: DZL-4R-47 thru 55, 1957 (Box 237)
  - Aerial Photographs: DZL-5R-105 thru 113, 1957 (Box 237)
  - Aerial Photographs: DZL-1R-225 thru 229, 1957 (Box 237)
  - Aerial Photographs: DZL-10R-8 thru 16, 1957 (Box 237)
  - Aerial Photographs: DZL-5R-160, 1957 (Box 237)
  - Aerial Photographs: 863: 76-100, 1960 (Box 237)
  - Aerial Photographs: 863: 125-150, 1960 (Box 237)
  - Aerial Photographs: 863: 51-75, 1961 (Box 237)
  - Aerial Photographs: 863: 0-25, 1961 (Box 237)
  - Aerial Photographs: 863: 25-50, 1961 (Box 237)
  - Aerial Photographs: 863: 101-125, 1961 (Box 237)
  - Aerial Photographs: 889: 1- 95, 1961 (Box 237)
  - Crozer Coal & Land Co. Interior Tracts for Topographic Property Map of Lynco, West Virginia, 1956/09/24 (Box 237)
  - Crozer Coal & Land Co. Property Corners, line Bearings and Distances for Topographic Property Map of Lynco, West Virginia, 1956/09/24 (Box 237)
  - Photo index and Model layout of Pocahontas Coal Field for Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., Pocahontas, Virginia, 1961/11/07 (Box 237)
  - Map of Itmann Mine workings, Beckley Seam, 1974/09/12 (Box 237)
  - Miscellaneous Aerial Photographs, 1950-1964 (Box 237)